Gabriela Perez-Quesada

 $\label{eq:Citizenship: EU-Italian} \\ \text{Utrecht, NL - Phone: } +31\text{-}06\text{-}33659597$

Email: gperezq@ksu.edu

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/gabriela-perez-quesada Website: https://sites.google.com/view/gperezquesada

Last updated: December 21, 2021

SUMMARY

I am a motivated PhD candidate in Agricultural Economics at Kansas State University. My research interests are in agricultural production, environmental and resource economics, and applied econometrics. I have strong quantitative skills and I am comfortable with managing large datasets, advanced statistical modeling, and computer programming. I am especially motivated by interdisciplinary research. As a trainee in the National Science Foundation (NSF)-Rural Resource Resiliency Traineeship Program, I have conducted interdisciplinary research to address the complexities around rural Food, Energy, and Water Systems.

EDUCATION

Kansas State University.

2022

Ph.D. Agricultural Economics

Dissertation: Essays on the Economics of Groundwater Depletion and Management in Irrigated Agriculture. (Job Market Paper)

Kansas State University.

2021

Sustainable Food, Energy, Water Graduate Certificate

Universidad de la República, Uruguay.

2017

M.S. International Economics

Technical efficiency measurement: an application on dairy farms in Uruguay. (Link)

Universidad de la República, Uruguay.

2012

B.A. Economics

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Graduate Research Assistant

2018-present

Kansas State University, Department of Agricultural Economics.

- Lessons from local governance and collective action efforts to manage irrigation with-drawals in Kansas. (Link)

Graduate Research Assistant

2015-present

Universidad de la República, School of Agronomy.

- Farm management systems: technical efficiencies differences and technology gap of Uruguay's dairy farms. (Link)

Rural Resource Resiliency NSF Research Trainee

2018-2021

Kansas State University (Link)

- A systematic review of spatial-temporal scale challenges in sociohydrology. (Link)

Graduate Research Assistant

2017 - 2018

Universidad de la República, Institute of Economics.

- Achieving sustainable development goals on socially inclusive and sustainable water through fiscal and pricing reforms in Uruguay.

Consultant Apr-July 2018

Inter-American Development Bank (BID).

- Estimated the technology gaps among small and medium cattle producers in Uruguay using the Total Factor Productivity approach.

Consultant May-Sept 2017

Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO).

- Contributed to the elaboration of the National Voluntary Review on the implementation of the 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development (Link)

Research and Policy Analysis Officer

Jan-Sept 2016

Ministry of Economy, Uruguay

- Conducted data analysis for the design of trade policy instruments.

Consultant Aug 2013-Feb 2014

National Agricultural Research Institute, Uruguay.

- Identified patterns in the adoption of technology among farmers in Uruguay.

Policy Analysis Officer

Aug 2013-Feb 2014

Ministry of Livestock, Agriculture and Fisheries, Uruguay.

- Implemented public programs to increase the competitiveness of farmers and production chains.

Consultant Mar 2013-Aug 2013

National Institute of Statistics, Uruguay.

- Analyzed data for the elaboration of the Consumer Price Index.

PEER REVIEWED JOURNAL ARTICLES

Fisher A, Miller J. A., Nottingham E., Wiederstein T., Krueger L., Perez-Quesada G., Sanderson M. R., and Hutchinson S. L. 2021. A systematic review of spatial-temporal scale challenges in sociohydrology. Frontiers in Water, 3:730169. (Link)

Perez-Quesada, G. and N.P. Hendricks. 2021. Lessons from local governance and collective action efforts to manage irrigation withdrawals in Kansas. Agricultural Water Management, 247:106736. (Link)

Garía-Suárez, F. and G. Perez-Quesada. 2019. Farm management systems: technical efficiencies differences and technology gap of Uruguay's dairy farms. Estudios Económicos, 36(72), 91-115. (Link)

Perez-Quesada, G. and F. Garía-Suárez. 2018. Technical efficiency measurement: an application on dairy farms in Uruguay. Economía Agraria, 20: 16-29. (Link)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Software: Stata, R, R GIS, ArcGIS, LaTex. Language: Spanish (native), English (fluent).